Marcus Loo Vergara

Oslo, Norway

☎ NO +47 411 78 583 • @ marcus.loo.vergara@gmail.com • ♦ bitsauce.github.io

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

M.Sc. in Computer Science. Graduated from the Norwegian University of Science and Technology June 2019. Specializing in computer graphics and computer vision, with additional interest in deep learning-based methods. Self-motivated, quick learner, and enjoy collaborating with others.

• C/C++

• OptiX & CUDA

• OpenGL & GLSL

Python

• Deep Learning

• Keras, PyTorch & TensorFlow

TCP & UDP

• Windows & Linux

• JavaScript, HTML & CSS

EDUCATION

Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Trondheim, Norway

Master of Science in Computer Science

• Specializing in computer graphics, computer vision, and deep learning

Aug 2013 – Jun 2019 GPA: 3.1/5

University of California, San Diego, San Diego, USA

Additional Studies, Computer Science

• Studying at UC San Diego as part of my degree

Oct 2017 - Jun 2018

GPA: 3.5/4

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Graphics Programmer at Funcom, Oslo, Norway

Full-time position as a Unreal Engine rendering programmer:

Oct 2019 - Present

- Researching modern rendering techniques and extending Unreal Engine's rendering capabilities with e.g. DX12 bindless textures, texel density tools, decal importing tools, etc.
- Focused on making efficient UE workflows for artists and other users
- Fulfilling internal support and debugging of reported rendering issues

Graphics Engineering Intern at Sony Interactive Entertainment, San Mateo, USA

Jul 2018 – Sep 2018

Internship at SIEA's Global Developer Technology Group

• Implemented a physically-based shading model running the PlayStation 4

- Investigated tools for automatically extracting and analyzing GPU performance data
- Exposure to low-level programming for specialized hardware

Software Developer at Grabster, Trondheim, Norway

Summer job assisting a start-up with app development

Jul 2017 – Aug 2017

- Grabster was a food-selling marketplace app for iOS and Android
- Implemented screen navigation and backend functionality for the Android app (React Native)

Teaching Assistant at the Norwegian University of Science and Technology

Aug 2015 – May 2019

On-campus part-time job assisting students

- Support and advising in solving theoretical and practical questions
- Graded assignments
- Assigned subjects:
 - Jan 2019 May 2019: Computer vision and deep learning
 - Jan 2016 May 2017: Procedural and object-oriented programming (C++)
 - Aug 2015 Dec 2015: Computers and digital design (Assembly programming)

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Reinforcement Learning for Autonomous Vehicles, Thesis

Sep 2019 - Present

Used state-of-the-art deep reinforcement learning methods to teach a simulated car to drive inside the open-source driving simulator, *CARLA*

- Implemented a custom version of the *Proximal Policy Optimization* reinforcement learning method with *Python* and *TensorFlow*
- Created an OpenAI gym-like environment that works with CARLA to make RL research in CARLA easier
- Substantially decreased training time by scaling the output mean of each action's Gaussian distributions to the action's respective limits
- Video of results: https://youtu.be/iF502iJKTIY

Ray-traced Soft Shadows, CSE 274 Course project

Mar 2018

Used NVIDIA's OptiX ray tracer to implement Axis-Aligned Filtering for Interactive Sampled Soft Shadows

- Provided a fundamental understanding of the use of frequency analysis in ray tracing
- Achieved interactive framerates of about 5-30 FPS on a NVIDIA GTX 970

Game Engine Programming, Side-project

2010 - Present

Writing a game engine from scratch in C++

- Ongoing side-project since 2010
- Uses OpenGL 4.2 and Simple DirectMedia Library to render to the screen
- Intended to serve as a mode of learning the inner-workings of game engines
- Developed alongside an infinite, procedurally-generated, sandbox game
 - See my homepage, bitsauce.github.io, for more information regarding these and other projects

MISCELLANEOUS

Teaching Assistant Training, Norwegian University of Science and Technology

Feb 2019 – May 2019

Certificate of attending a 20-hour pedagogical training course for teaching assistants.

Abakus GameDev, Norwegian University of Science and Technology

Co-founder and leader of student organization *Abakus GameDev* – a student organization for people who enjoy making games, discussing their development, design, and the industry in general

- Responsible for creating a socket-based framework that was used for AI competitions
- Participates in meetings, discussing workshop ideas and advertising
- Held a presentation on deep reinforcement learning for games